NETS 150 Homework 5 - Final Project
Raunaq Singh

Project Name: InstructorRank

“With great power, comes great responsibility” - Voltaire

Summary: In this project, I "graded" TAs based off of their activity on Piazza. Using the Piazza API, the program gets the posts for a specific course (which the user provides) and then records the following statistics for each TA- number of responses, the actual contents of the responses, the total and average response times, the total and average response lengths (characters), and lastly, the total and average number of 'Thanks!' they received on Piazza. I then calculated cosine similarities of responses for each TA and conducted a modified PageRank algorithm on the TAs (described in more detail below). Finally, I constructed a simple formula which used all of these metrics in order to give the TAs scores for their Piazza performance.

Note: This project was not intended to diminish the efforts of any TAs. The results of the algorithm should not be taken too seriously.


Project Categories:

• Document Search - Part of my assessment of the instructors on Piazza was how similar their responses were to one another. In order to do this, for each instructor, I found the cosine similarity between every pair of responses and averaged these values to find a measure of similarity among all of their responses.

• Information Networks (World Wide Web) - Utilized the Piazza API in order to retrieve the data behind the project.

• Graph Algorithms - Specifically, I used a modified version of the "Scaled" PageRank algorithm. On Piazza, instructors can publicly endorse the answers of other instructors, and in this way, endorse other instructors themselves. So, I kept a track of these endorsements, made a graph with vertices for the instructors that had directed edges from instructor i to j if i endorsed one of j's answers on Piazza. These edges also had weights, and the weight for the edge (i,j) was the number of times instructor i endorsed one of j's answers. From there, I used the "Random Surfer" model of PageRank, while also factoring in the weights of the edges.


Work Breakdown: I completed this project on my own.
